<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" 
xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    
        
            <link href="https://alansartlog.com/tags/other/rss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"  />
            <title>Alan&#39;s Art Log - Tag:other</title>
            <link type="text/html" href="https://alansartlog.com/tags/other" rel="alternate"/>
            <id>https://alansartlog.com/tags/other</id>
        
    
    <subtitle>Paintings, sketches, tutorials, videos, and art related DIY projects.</subtitle>
    <category term="Art"></category>
    <icon>https://alansartlog.com/resources/images/pencil-logo-icon-150x150.jpg</icon>
    
    <updated>2019-02-16T23:35:34+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Alan North</name>
        <email>alansartlog@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    
    <rights>© Copyright 2017-2019 Alan North - All rights reserved unless otherwise stated.</rights>

    
        <entry>
    
    <title>So... YouTube Enabled Unskippable Ads Without Asking Me</title>
    <link href="https://alansartlog.com/2018/11/so...-youtube-enabled-unskippable-ads-without-asking-me"/>
    <id>https://alansartlog.com/2018/11/so...-youtube-enabled-unskippable-ads-without-asking-me</id>
    
    
    
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm furious. </p>
<p>I never wanted to add unskippable ads. </p>
<p>Don't know exactly when this happened. Worst part is there's no option to batch remove the ads, so I had to go one by one to disable them. I think I got them all but <strong>if you find a video of mine with unskippable* ads please contact me so I can remove them.</strong></p>
<p>I only found out because I was turning off monetization for an outdated video and noticed it was on. I had seen lately that there had been a drop in views/revenues lately which I thought was a bit odd, but put it down to one of those random fluctuations, or maybe because I wasn't posting as frequently, but looking at my timeline now it's quite clear it was the unskippable ads.</p>
<p>So, sorry for everyone who suffered through that.</p>
<p>Hopefully in the future I can make enough of patreons and donations that I can disable them completely, but for now, unfortunately, I need the money to buy materials for projects, etc.</p>
<p>*I believe "unskippable" ads below the 5 second skip timer don't count. It's if they're longer than that.</p>]]></content>
    
    <link rel="service.post" type="text/html" href="https://alansartlog.com/2018/11/so...-youtube-enabled-unskippable-ads-without-asking-me#disqus_thread" title="Comment"/>
    
        <category term="https://alansartlog.com/tags/other" label="other"></category>
    
    
    <updated>2018-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
</entry>

    
</feed>
