<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" 
xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    
        
            <link href="https://alansartlog.com/tags/lifehacks/rss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"  />
            <title>Alan&#39;s Art Log - Tag:lifehacks</title>
            <link type="text/html" href="https://alansartlog.com/tags/lifehacks" rel="alternate"/>
            <id>https://alansartlog.com/tags/lifehacks</id
        
    
    <subtitle>Paintings, sketches, tutorials, videos, and art related DIY projects.</subtitle>
    <category term="Art"></category>
    <icon>https://alansartlog.com/resources/images/pencil-logo-icon-150x150.jpg</icon>
    
    <updated>2019-02-16T23:35:34+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Alan North</name>
        <email>alansartlog@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    
    <rights>© Copyright 2017-2019 Alan North - All rights reserved unless otherwise stated.</rights>

    
        <entry>
    
    <title>Quick Tip - How to Tighten Tripod Legs</title>
    <link href="https://alansartlog.com/2016/11/tripod-quick-tip"/>
    <id>https://alansartlog.com/2016/11/tripod-quick-tip</id>
    
    
    
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qLNLrjWVCGo?autoplay=1" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>I didn't finish the video I really wanted to do (on sculpting with polymer clay) so this is just a quick tip. It won't work for all tripods, but it should work for most of the ones that use hinges to tighten the legs.</p>
<p><a class="read-more" href="/2016/11/tripod-quick-tip">Read More…</a></p>]]></content>
    
    <link rel="service.post" type="text/html" href="https://alansartlog.com/2016/11/tripod-quick-tip#disqus_thread" title="Comment"/>
    
        <category term="https://alansartlog.com/tags/diy" label="diy"></category>
    
        <category term="https://alansartlog.com/tags/lifehacks" label="lifehacks"></category>
    
        <category term="https://alansartlog.com/tags/recordingediting-tools" label="recording/editing tools"></category>
    
        <category term="https://alansartlog.com/tags/toolssoftware" label="tools/software"></category>
    
    
    <updated>2016-11-17T17:38:57+00:00</updated>
</entry>

    
        <entry>
    
        <media:thumbnail url="https://alansartlog.com//resources/uploads/modified-can.jpg"/>
        
    
    <title>Easily Pour Paint from Small Cans</title>
    <link href="https://alansartlog.com/2015/12/easily-pour-paint-from-small-cans"/>
    <id>https://alansartlog.com/2015/12/easily-pour-paint-from-small-cans</id>
    
    
    
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can also find this post as an <a href="http://www.instructables.com/id/Easily-Pour-Paint-From-Small-Cans/">Instructable</a></p>
<h1 id="smallupdate">Small Update</h1>
<p>I’d hoped to have my drawers done by now but they’ve taken longer than planned even though I’ve been working an average of one hour a day for a month, which is incredibly productive given my state. The structure is finished but it’s the little details that are taking a long time. I don’t want to stop posting completely though so in the meantime I’ll be making a few posts about the things I did to make the project easier on myself. These will technically be posted in reverse order that I made them because I only have the prototypes now, I didn’t actually make the finished tools.</p>
<p>Also since figuring out a method to get paid I’ve been working on creating a Patreon, and getting a YouTube channel set up and everything so I’ve been very busy. It’s not done yet, but if you want to support me check it out&nbsp;and/or share my posts.</p>
<h1 id="paintcans">Paint Cans</h1>
<p>We all know what a pain it is to pour paint out. I tried to google to see if there was some sort of life hack for this but found none so I made my own. I honestly don’t even know why we still use cans shaped like they are. I get not using plastic because the metal is probably easier to recycle and more resistant (plus it keeps out light), but surely they could add better lids. This isn’t so much a problem on big cans for me, so this solution doesn’t work for them. With bigger cans you usually need to use large amounts at once and you tend to use the can all at once (say to paint a room) so controlling the amount isn’t such a problem. But with small cans this works great and I’m sure you could modify this to something larger if you find a large enough bottle, or you could pour larger cans into smaller empty ones and reuse them if say you bought something in bulk but only use a small amount at a time.</p>
<p><a class="read-more" href="/2015/12/easily-pour-paint-from-small-cans">Read More…</a></p>]]></content>
    
    <link rel="service.post" type="text/html" href="https://alansartlog.com/2015/12/easily-pour-paint-from-small-cans#disqus_thread" title="Comment"/>
    
        <category term="https://alansartlog.com/tags/diy" label="diy"></category>
    
        <category term="https://alansartlog.com/tags/lifehacks" label="lifehacks"></category>
    
        <category term="https://alansartlog.com/tags/toolssoftware" label="tools/software"></category>
    
    
    <updated>2015-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
</entry>

    
</feed>